i am only going to do one
take on this because it's going to be a
long one it's going to be a long story
so even if i mess up it's going to keep
going you didn't know i already did that
did you
because i i know i have some mess-ups in
my video but generally when i mess up
too much i just restart
i today is my one year anniversary for
game b
one year ago i was planning on going
live for my first
broadcast of together tech's live board
meeting where i'm like whoever shows up
shows up i'm gonna go live at the same
time every
every week and um while preparing for
that
i got a message from remzy of common
planet
to had i heard of game b and there was a
zoom call about to go on like it was
happening right now
if i wanted to come it was happening
right now and so i jumped on the zoom
call
and over the next few days and weeks i
consumed a ton of game b
content a lot of the podcasts a lot of
jordan hall stuff
and daniel ochtenberger i
was so excited to find the gamebee
community during the facebook group
um and this i think one of the biggest
draws was the game bee cafe in the very
beginning
this time last year there was a zoom
account that you could just pop into at
any time and there would be people there
and it dissipated very fast over the
next few days even
and then weeks where you'd have to wait
in there for an hour in order for
someone to come in
but i met some amazing people in that
cafe
as well as then needing that cafe and
not having it anymore reaching out to
people within the game b
space and starting conversations
i came into game b very much before
because i'd been
working on it for years with an idea on
how we saved the world i'm like i know
how we create amy i know i know
i came in with a lot of puppy energy and
a year later my puppy energy has
dissipated because it's like i've found
a home a community
people who not just in the game b space
but also in my regular life
it's like okay i don't necessarily need
to bring up game b topics
all day every day i still do because i
have a space to talk about those things
in
but what i have learned over the last
year i wanted to share so i have
seven things that i've learned and then
a little bit of an advice or a call to
action for
everyone else if they want to also get a
lot out of game b
but i did want to acknowledge i totally
came into view game b a year ago with
this i know how to
i know how to we can create game b and
although i still feel like this thing
inside of me is
absolutely how we save the world in
great game b
i get game b on another level of like
thank god i'm not alone thank god my
thing
isn't the only thing out there and i
have found
people who are doing this important work
so one of the big lessons i have learned
is diversity
and i came in with that as one of my top
three things that the world
tech cooperative needed to have
diversity transparency
and fun it needed to be an enjoyable
process whatever we were doing and
although this was still my meaning of
diversity before getting into game b
and truly experiencing this level of
diversity
is it has made it a lived experience
instead of just a cognitive one
where the diversity i mean is very much
at the individual level
every individual is a diverse microcosm
of their experiences their genetics
their
karma their whatever you want to call it
and
coming to game b and and realizing how
much we have in common but also how
diverse we are
there's i've never sat at a table and
not found some things that are like oh
that you do
and also some things that are like what
really you think that way interesting
and so the diversity even when i'm
sitting at a table full of you know
white able-bodied men at a table zoom
table
a virtual table the diversity of thought
that's there
is a lot more diverse than other
[Music]
panels and things that i've been on
where it's been like force diversity
forced visible diversity where we all
think the same but we look different
versus right this is this is different i
can't just
say like this is the truth and then it's
taken as the truth because
this isn't everyone's truth we don't all
have the same experience
what we do have in common is the game b
experience and so we might all know what
david who david uh
david's daniel schweichtenberger or
jordan hall are and what omni win means
what anti-ravalrus means
but we come to it from different areas
and some people know integral theory and
some people don't and some people
are from um the intellectual dark web
and some people
never would like so we love jordan
peterson so we hate jordan peterson like
it's it's very um
i'm saying it's very diverse but but i
have found the
the true like the flavor of diversity
has gotten deeper
when it's the diversity that i'm open to
so that is the first thing that i wanted
to share that i've learned
um two that this keeps coming up again
this whole year
is that game b the magic of game b
happens in conversations
it doesn't happen on the facebook group
um it happens
in zoom rooms and on on i'm sure in
person
although i've met very few gambie people
in person it happens and not even just
the easy fun conversations it happens in
the conflict it happens
in the difficult conversations as well
that those have been some of the most
rewarding ones that i've had
are the ones where i'm like damn do i
have to have this conversation
yeah because it's mine to have no one
else has to have that conversation if
they don't want to
and that has been one of the things game
b has given me when i've been struggling
with something when i've been struggling
with a concept
um for instance blockchain i'm still not
100 sure blockchain is the solution
everyone thinks it is
but when i'm like no it's just not it's
just no so i reached out and asked the
game b space like who is passionate
about it
and can sit with me and explain it and
that was one of the most rewarding
conversations
it wasn't like i understood it but i'm
like there's something
there's all these things that i have an
issue with and so sitting with someone
and seeing it from their point of view i
was like okay yeah i see more what
what the beauty is here and so
the conversation is where the magic
happens and i'm so grateful for all of
the conversations
i'm sure it's been hundreds of hours for
sure of conversations i've had over
the course of the last year
oh this one's a big one for the new
gaming people if you want to take this
with it
is um there's an overwhelming amount of
game b information
you cannot catch up on it you cannot
keep up with it
and so the faster you know that the
faster you can be like
okay i don't need to then like you can't
possibly
even keep up with the current podcasts
that jordan hall daniel schmeckenberger
schwalkenberger and um
eric and brent are are doing right like
even the current ones you can't keep up
with let alone
all of rebel wisdom and all of their
guests and all of you know jim rutt and
his guests and
like it's there's too much you can't you
can't do it so find what is yours to
learn
what is that like what calls to you what
actually is yours to learn because
um i know i contain all the knowledge i
need i don't need homework from other
people
i don't need to to do any more research
on the outside
and nor does anybody else come be part
of conversations do what is yours to do
including listening to those things if
they call to you
but you don't need to it's not
like you need to take the course and
then start playing game b
there is no course being in the chaos is
is pretty pretty pretty gamey oh
so i follow my interests and
then i can bring them to the
conversation so most recently
i've fallen down this rabbit hole of
anti-mlm which is multi-level marketing
and it is bringing something into game b
through me
that is very powerful um that's not
going to be on the reading list right
go read the anti-mlm content it's like
right because i can bring that to it
and so if we're all consuming the same
content
how do we have how do we maintain that
diversity right so why not go and
look at what interests you and have the
conversations
with game b people bring that
information to the conversation
experience i have here oh just that
everything is an experience so there
really isn't any failure
because i have tried so many things over
the last year and some of them have
gotten crickets and some of them got
more traction
and it's like what do i enjoy what do i
what do other people enjoy what do i
have to offer and just keep
finding the next experience and the next
experience
and i'm having fun i'm having fun doing
it a failing and trying new things and
learning from them
and watching other people do the same
thing and learning from each other
oh this is i feel like i want to leave
five till the end
are let's go do six first technology oh
technology is not the solution
everyone comes into game b i was not
alone we need a new social media
platform
new technology and jim wrote very very
much
it's like technology is not the answer
like you don't even know what this this
is
and i still think technology is a big
piece of the answer
but it's not the answer because the same
idea comes up all the time and it's like
it's the meta answer like right why are
we keep creating recreating the same
thing and failing how do we learn to
work together
and create it together how do we come up
how do we solve the meta problem
of marketing and resources
and people involved so that we can have
a successful one
one of them be successful that we can go
on that one instead of facebook but that
technology is not
the answer that i thought it was a year
ago today
oh one of the biggest learnings
that i got from consuming other people's
content i believe it was jb wheel
uh talking about utopia and why it's not
obtainable
and how because i have a utopian idea
i'm like how beautiful
that mine will never be realized and
normal any of yours
but in working towards them and this is
not what jamie will say this is my
interpretation jamie will the point was
that utopians can't be achieved because
if you
maximize for a value you it costs you
all other values
so if you maximize for freedom it's
going to cost you everything else if you
maximize for justice it's going to cost
you everything else
and whatever your idea of utopia is it's
going to maximize for your values right
even if it's a combination of values
it's your values
that you're then going to have to
enforce on everyone else and it costs
you every other value
and so my one of my biggest learnings is
that
we don't have to agree why game a is
broken
everyone has their very strong like we
can't do
anything until we fix money we can't do
anything until private property we can't
do anything until we have the technology
we don't have to agree on what that
broken piece
is just that it's broken and there's so
many there can be so many people working
on different issues we can fix them all
so it's okay that yours you just can't
if step one is get everyone on board my
idea
step one's broken step one is like how
do i get
some people on board my idea so we can
work with it that's that works out
better
we don't have to agree on gay memes
broken we don't have to agree on our
beautiful utopian version of
of game b sorry i just said game b
tonight why game a is broken we don't
have to agree on our beautiful utopian
idea of green bee
just the commonality that's omniwood and
anti-rivalrous
and that can mean different things to
different people all we have to do is
agree on a step forward
and that's very different than needing
to agree on what where we're starting
from or where we're going it's just a
step forward and for me that's solution
raising what has come
through me into the world in game b very
much with
a lot of game b people involved in it
and uh one of the biggest
learnings i've had and i think that a
lot of us have this
is number seven which is i'm not alone
i've found my people i've found the
people who are
saving the world who had a deep down
level their whole lives have been
looking for this
whether they were playing game a or not
they
i found my people and i'm not alone it's
not all on me i don't need to save the
entire world i don't need to create an
entire global tech cooperative by myself
i found my people and so whether you're
just joining game b
or whether you've been here for a really
long time or whether you haven't found
it and you're writing this video
and you want to come join game b uh
i want to offer that you are enough
right now you don't need to learn
anymore
you don't need to be anymore you just
need to find your people
and start having the conversations a
conversation in and of itself
is powerful you will grow they will grow
it's not on you to make them grow
and new ideas will emerge one of the
most powerful conversations i have had
besides the one a few one-off ones that
i can look at and be like oh that was a
powerful one
um the odd conversation together tech
not odd sorry it happens all the time
but i would say about 60 to 70 of the
sessions we have end up with at least 15
to 20 minutes of like oh i really
enjoyed that conversation
but that was designed around a
technology cooperative our omega
conversations that happen every
wednesday with a handful of us
they're the most they're the most
long-lasting that's not really true
together tech happened
a little bit before and it's still
happening but um they're more consistent
i feel like i've actually shown up to
more omega conversations than together
tech ones
i've maybe missed anyway that's not the
point that
finding a group of people that you can
meet with weekly to discuss
the game be stuff that is arising
whether it's everyone listen to daniel
schmuckenberger's podcast and then let's
talk about it or like more like a book
club or more just
how we started it which was let's
practice a manga rule
let's let's practice practice to make a
rule now if we watched it we probably
tried in the beginning we're not even
really trying it's like
a natural emergence i'm getting to know
people and um both we're practicing it
less we interrupt each other more and
get
misunderstanding and also
practicing it more in a deeper level in
between sessions and like oh did i step
on your toes
there and did this did this happen
because but there's
magic that is arising and so i get it
coming into game b
and one scene what i just said about
diversity i mean like this is not
diverse
there is a lot of white men there's a
lot of white men there isn't there isn't
enough women there isn't enough people
of color there isn't enough queerness
there isn't
there is enough neurodiversity
beautifully
i think most people in game b are
neurodiverse but there isn't necessarily
enough
uh diversity in different abilities
and yet there is enough diversity
because it's the individuals that are
drawn here and i don't ever want to not
accept an individual because we're
trying to make a quota
i invite you
to find your people put up a post asking
to discuss what you want to discuss
put a time out and see who shows up and
if no one shows up learn from that and
if everyone shows up
learn from that but enjoy whoever does
show up and have the conversation with
them
if that's too much for you come to the
solution raisings you kick up to the
idea cafes go to ed to eric otherwise
known as liberate mankind on facebook
it's tuesday sessions that are open to
everybody
that are posted rather regularly in the
game b space
go to the stoa go rebel wisdom go to the
places where you're actually having
conversations with people
because that is where game b is going to
emerge from it is coming in
in all of these corners and all of these
projects together tech is focusing
on um the projects how we can hold our
own projects that we that are our babies
and how do we keep hold of them until
we're ready to like maybe loosen the
grip and worked and
we're like yeah people can come onto my
project but it's still mine
how do we emerge into creating something
together that's what i'm exploring with
solution raising
and this new mlm idea that's coming
through me through my anti-mlm content
like well this is interesting i didn't
see this going there
that will be coming up in the next few
weeks
here on my youtube channel i'll probably
be sharing it in the gamebee facebook
group as well
happy anniversary to me finding game b
on friday the 13th
september september friday the 13th
2019. who knew what year was in store
for me for the world and now a year
later
i feel like i've come so far and game b
has come so far and yet i get that to be
outside it doesn't look that way
if you're not in it if you're not having
the conversations with people if you're
not one of the nodes in the network
if you're just looking at the nodes and
studying them that doesn't work if
you're actually having the conversations
with people and sharing your ideas and
getting critique on them and
offering your critique of other people's
you can start to see the magic unfolding
it is coming together there are so many
amazing projects so many amazing people
working in the game b
space and adjacent to the game b space
i have so much hope for the future and i
no longer fee i have days where i still
feel like the world's on my shoulders
the weight of the world
but i'm not alone
there is so many people working towards
an omnium anti-rivalrous future
and we're dealing with our own ego and
our own emotions that
are stop us in the way of that
and i invite you to join in any way you
can
use the facebook page as a
community hub right to find those people
but have actual conversations
have real conversations not in the real
world right now but on zoom
we are a global community and that is so
powerful especially in this time of
covid
to be able to witness each other and how
our governments are handling it and our
communities are handling it
if you're waiting for the leadership to
come up with game b
they're not going to it's going to
emerge
from hundreds or thousands of people
doing all of these little things and
coming
and figuring it out together this is one
of my insights i've had along the way
and other people might not share it and
that is totally fine
i don't think if game a has worked for
you
you're gonna be actually one of the
instrumental people in creating game b
and i don't mean that disparagingly i
just mean if game a worked for you you
can't envision game b
in the same way that game b that people
who game aid
does not and did not work for can and
that is where the diversity comes in
is it can work for you in kind of one
way and so you can look for anyone even
who game a works
for 100 can find ways it doesn't and try
and fix it that's where we don't have to
agree that
how it's broken but the more it's broken
for you
the more you're able to figure out how
to fix it for everyone as long as you're
not trying to impose that on everyone
else and that's one of my biggest
learnings is how much
even though i didn't see my vision as
imposing on other people
all the ways that it was when i felt
other people's visions were imposing on
me
and then looking like where's that
learning in mind and where's looking for
any time i'm triggered any time there's
conflict if it's with a person is it my
conflict about them
or is it actually a conflict and do we
need to deal with it
but that if you're waiting for jordan
hall to come up with a solution and
present it to you if you're waiting for
daniel schmucktenberger and jim rutt to
be like here you go here's game b
jump on board it's so not happening i
don't think they have the capability to
do that
because they've envisioned what game b
could be but it's going to be us who
game a is way more broken for
people who don't have a platform who
don't have a voice who aren't as
articulate
who have like a spark of an idea because
like i'm seeing it happen
i'm seeing it happen but there's also
something deep down where it's like if
you're waiting for them
you're missing the point you're the
person who's going to
do your piece of it if you're waiting
for them to do something
they're not doing it you're getting
angry at them for not doing it it's
because it's yours to do
it's yours to do and i truly don't think
they're the ones who are going to come
up with the things that are actually
going to amalgamate to make game b
but if they do i'm happy i'm happy for
it i'll jump on board with it for sure
i'm jumping on board with
whatever comes out of it but
and they're also not as interconnected
as the rest of us in the
the base because they're really busy and
doing other things and they're on
podcasts and they're getting like the
message out in the word out
as opposed to being able to have a
two-hour conversation on a wednesday
afternoon
about omega rule and about what's
emerging in our own lives
they're you know able to have a tech
cooperative
we're able to have a tech cooperative
meeting that is two hours a week right
an hour on fridays for our board meeting
in an hour for round table and see what
is generated in that space
even though we have busy lives as well
so this is it 21 minutes i don't want to
keep it much longer
welcome to game b and happy anniversary
to me
take care